
[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What does the control unit do?",
    "choices": [
      "holds all the registers",
      "performs all the calculations in the CPU",
      "coordinates all the components of the cpu"
    ],
    "topic": "maths",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "coordinates all the components of the cpu"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What does the arithmetic logic unit do?",
    "choices": [
      "holds the results of arithmatic calculations",
      "performs arithmetic and logical operations on data",
      "coordinates all the components of the CPU"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "performs arithmetic and logical operations on data"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What does the accumulator do?",
    "choices": [
      "stores the results of the calculations",
      "sends control signals to parts of the CPU",
      "decodes instructions"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "stores the results of the calculations"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What does the current instruction register do?",
    "choices": [
      "stores all the instructions that are to be excecuted ",
      "stores the address of the current instruction to be excecuted",
      "it temporarily stores the instruction that is currently being decoded or excecuted"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "it temporarily stores the instruction that is currently being decoded or excecuted"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What does the memory address register do?",
    "choices": [
      "sends address signals to other parts of the CPU",
      "stores memory addresses for data that is being fetched or stored",
      "reads addresses from main memory"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "stores memory addresses for data that is being fetched or stored"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What does the memory data register do?",
    "choices": [
      "temporarily holds the data that is being transferred to and from memory",
      "stores the address of the next piece of data to be fetched",
      "sends read or write signals to Main memory"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "temporarily holds the data that is being transferred to and from memory"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Name the three buses in a CPU?",
    "choices": [
      "control, arithmatic, system",
      "data, memory, logic",
      "control, address, data"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "control, address, data"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What does the address bus do?",
    "choices": [
      "carries memory addresses that identify where the data is being read from or written to",
      "sends read or write signals to Main memory",
      "stores memory addresses for data that is being fetched or stored"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "carries memory addresses that identify where the data is being read from or written to"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What does the data bus do?",
    "choices": [
      "carries the binary 1's and 0's that make up the actual information being transmitted around the CPU",
      "coordinates all the components of the cpu",
      "sends read or write signals to Main memory"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "carries the binary 1's and 0's that make up the actual information being transmitted around the CPU"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "What does the control bus do?",
    "choices": [
      "controls all the instructions that are fetched",
      "temporarily stores the instruction that is currently being decoded or excecuted",
      "carries control and command signals to and from every other component of the CPU"
    ],
    "topic": "Structure and function of the processor",
    "difficulty": "EASY",
    "answer": "carries control and command signals to and from every other component of the CPU"
  }
]